# **DICKSON D. DJIKUNU**

# GPS GN07204096 | +233 54 6969 778 | ddicksondjikunu@gmail.com

# **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Resourceful, meticulous IT-oriented person with over 4 years of experience in strategic problemsolving using Information Technologies, system troubleshooting, customer relationship management, software development, general IT equipment maintenance, and management. Team player with strong technical proficiency and commitment to accuracy.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Technical Officer:** 

#### **Akim State University College**

August 2017 to 2021

- Providing technical support and advice for employees and students in need of assistance.
- Designing, developing, and maintaining equipment to ensure effective and safe use.
- Testing and evaluating new technologies.
- Conducting electrical safety tests on computer equipment and other new technology.
- Providing support, including procedural documentation and relevant reports.
- Following diagrams and written instructions to repair a fault or set up a system.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults.

IT Technical Support Officer (Service Personnel)

# **Birim Central Municipal Assembly.**

Oct. 2021 to Oct. 2022

- Installations and configuration of computer systems and applications.
- Diagnosing hardware and software faults.
- Talking to staff or clients through a series of actions, either face-to-face or over the phone, to help set up systems or resolve issues.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.
- Supporting the roll-out of new applications.
- Setting up new users' accounts and profiles and dealing with a fault or setting up a system.
- Testing and evaluating new technology.
- Conducting electrical safety checks on computer equipment.

#### Software Developer

#### Freelancer.

- Researching, designing, implementing, and managing software programs.
- Testing and evaluating new programs.
- Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications.
- Writing and implementing efficient code.
- Determining operational practicality.
- Developing quality assurance procedures.
- Deploying software tools, processes, and metrics.
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.
- Training users.
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts.

### Accounts Officer/ Claims Officer

# **Akim State College.**

Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2022

- Earned a good reputation for good attendance and hard work.
- Capturing of students' fees received and bank deposits.
- Financial Recording and booking of the Cafeteria.
- Inventory and Stocktaking of office supplies and cafeteria items.
- Banking money received from cashier point.
- Billing of students and checking diagnosis on billing sheet.
- Vetting of claims and data entry of student bills and other insurance companies.
- Reconciled operations database with accounting system information to calculate and determine monthly revenue.
- Evaluated expense reports for accuracy and adherence to company policies.
- Reviewed purchase documents and company receipts for reconciliation with statements.
- Staff documentation, record keeping, and preparation of Student Bills.
- Monitor customer accounts details for non-payment, delayed payment, and irregularities.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BSc. Computer Science**

August 2017 to Sept. 2021

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology

**WASSC** 

Sept. 2014 to May 2017

Akim State Snr. High School

#### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- WordPress Development
  WordPress.org
- BCMA Community Health Training Eastern Region
- Digital Workplace Experience Virtual Conference Series, 2022
- A 2-Days Strategic Career Development Seminar PMC 2021
- Music Production G-Digital Studio

#### **SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

- Strong leadership and people management skills
- Excellent level of attention to detail.
- Proficient in Microsoft Outlook, Word, Excel, and knowledge of CMS such as WordPress.
- Adept in multi-tasking and working in a fast-paced environment.
- Excellent written and oral communication skills.
- Results-driven with a can-do attitude.
- Enthusiastic and adaptable to new, challenging environments.
- Good programming skills with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, Java, and Python.
- Languages: Fluent in English and working knowledge of French, Twi, and Ewe.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

- Developed ODA Community forecasting news for the Akim Oda community.
- Initiated a payment system for Akim State College.

### **HOBBIES AND OTHER INTERESTS**

• Reading, Public Speaking, and Creative Writing.

**REFEREES:** Available upon request